<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="https://www.bracco.com"  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>Bracco Corporate</title>
 <link>https://www.bracco.com</link>
 <description></description>
 <language>en-gb</language>
<item>
 <title>en-usa-vueway</title>
 <link>https://www.bracco.com/en/en-usa-vueway</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;form-item form-type-item&quot;&gt;
  &lt;label&gt;Language &lt;/label&gt;
 United Kingdom - English
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;field-label&quot;&gt;Sommario:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://imaging.bracco.com/us-en/fda-approves-gadopiclenol-injection-us-market&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;FDA Approves&lt;br&gt;
Gadopiclenol Injection &lt;br&gt;
 for the U.S. market&lt;/a&gt;

          &lt;div class=&quot;field-label&quot;&gt;Immagine responsive 800x600:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.bracco.com/sites/bracco.com/files/slider-vueway800x600.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;    &lt;ul class=&quot;links inline&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;translation_it-it first last&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/it/it-usa-vueway&quot; title=&quot;it-usa-vueway&quot; class=&quot;translation-link&quot; xml:lang=&quot;it-it&quot;&gt;Italiano&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 08:34:56 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">875 at https://www.bracco.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>en-bracco-archivio</title>
 <link>https://www.bracco.com/en/en-bracco-archivio</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;form-item form-type-item&quot;&gt;
  &lt;label&gt;Language &lt;/label&gt;
 United Kingdom - English
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;field-label&quot;&gt;Sommario:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.archiviostoricobracco.com/en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Corporate heritage&lt;br&gt;
is a powerful &lt;br&gt;strategic lever &lt;br&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;imm-linkedin-desktop&quot; src=&quot;/sites/bracco.com/files/visit-the-bracco-historical-archive-n.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Visit Bracco Historical Archive&quot; width=&quot;137&quot; height=&quot;85&quot; style=&quot;max-width:130px!important; height:Auto!important;&quot;/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;imm-linkedin-mobile&quot; src=&quot;/sites/bracco.com/files/visit-the-bracco-historical-archive-resp-n.png&quot; width=&quot;137&quot; height=&quot;85&quot; style=&quot;max-width:130px!important; height:Auto!important;&quot; alt=&quot;Visit Bracco Historical Archive&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;          &lt;div class=&quot;field-label&quot;&gt;Immagine responsive 800x600:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.bracco.com/sites/bracco.com/files/archivio-storico-slider800x600.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;    &lt;ul class=&quot;links inline&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;translation_it-it first last&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/it/it-bracco-archivio&quot; title=&quot;it-bracco-archivio&quot; class=&quot;translation-link&quot; xml:lang=&quot;it-it&quot;&gt;Italiano&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 09:28:31 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">872 at https://www.bracco.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>en-slider-anniversary</title>
 <link>https://www.bracco.com/en/en-slider-anniversary</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;form-item form-type-item&quot;&gt;
  &lt;label&gt;Language &lt;/label&gt;
 United Kingdom - English
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;field-label&quot;&gt;Sommario:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://braccoanniversary.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;95 years of &lt;br&gt;curiosity, passion and innovation.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:16px!important; line-height:20px!important; display:inline-block;&quot;&gt;Learn the whole story at&lt;br&gt; 
braccoanniversary.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;          &lt;div class=&quot;field-label&quot;&gt;Immagine responsive 800x600:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.bracco.com/sites/bracco.com/files/bracco_95th_anni_banner1_responsive.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;    </description>
 <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 10:14:39 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">864 at https://www.bracco.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Philochem and Bracco Imaging collaborate on the development of a molecule for diagnostic applications</title>
 <link>https://www.bracco.com/en/news/philochem-and-bracco-imaging-collaborate-development-molecule-diagnostic-applications</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;form-item form-type-item&quot;&gt;
  &lt;label&gt;Language &lt;/label&gt;
 United Kingdom - English
&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;Philochem&lt;/span&gt;, a subsidiary of the &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;Philogen Group&lt;/span&gt;, and &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;Bracco Imaging&lt;/span&gt; today announce that they have entered into a license and collaboration agreement to develop and commercialize a &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;small organic molecule&lt;/span&gt; for &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;imaging applications&lt;/span&gt;, with proven ability to selectively detect a variety of &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;metastatic solid tumors&lt;/span&gt; in cancer patients, paving the way for a new approach to tumor diagnosis.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;Philogen and Bracco share an Italian heritage and operate globally in the pharmaceutical and biotech sectors. Bracco and Philochem will pioneer the &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;development of cutting-edge technologies&lt;/span&gt; for the discovery and optimization of &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;small molecule ligands&lt;/span&gt; that enable unprecedented specificity and sensitivity for the &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;imaging of solid tumors&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;Prof. Dr. Dario Neri&lt;/span&gt;, Member of the Board of Philochem and CEO of the Philogen Group, commented: “&lt;em&gt;We are extremely pleased to establish a new collaboration with Bracco Imaging, a leading global company in the image diagnostics field. This new collaboration will focus on the development and commercialization of a small molecule for imaging applications, which promises to improve the diagnosis, staging and monitoring of response-to-treatment for cancer patients. Both companies are committed to the development of the product and making it available to patients who may benefit from it&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;We are very excited about this collaboration with Philochem, a leader in the discovery and development of novel pharmaceutical and biopharmaceutical products. It demonstrates Bracco’s commitment to long-term value creation in medical imaging. Over the years, Bracco has built a portfolio of leading products across all imaging modalities and is continuing to invest in innovation to shape the future of precision imaging and improve people’s lives&lt;/em&gt;”, commented &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;Fulvio Renoldi Bracco&lt;/span&gt;, Vice-Chairman &amp;amp; CEO of Bracco Imaging.&lt;/p&gt;                Siena-Milan, Italy                &lt;span class=&quot;date-display-single&quot;&gt;03/22/2022&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;ul class=&quot;links inline&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;translation_it-it first last&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/it/news/philochem-e-bracco-imaging-accordo-lo-sviluppo-di-una-molecola-applicazioni-di-imaging&quot; title=&quot;Philochem e Bracco Imaging: accordo per lo sviluppo di una molecola per applicazioni di imaging diagnostico&quot; class=&quot;translation-link&quot; xml:lang=&quot;it-it&quot;&gt;Italiano&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 12:47:51 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">847 at https://www.bracco.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>AIforCOVID: “Best Scientific Collaboration Program of the Year”</title>
 <link>https://www.bracco.com/en/news/aiforcovid-best-scientific-collaboration-program-year</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;form-item form-type-item&quot;&gt;
  &lt;label&gt;Language &lt;/label&gt;
 United Kingdom - English
&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;/en/news/customized-anti-covid-treatments-available-thanks-centro-diagnostico-italiano-cdi-project&quot;&gt;AIforCOVID non-profit project&lt;/a&gt;, promoted during the &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;COVID-19 pandemic&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;/en/products/health-services&quot;&gt;CDI Centro Diagnostico Italiano&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/en/products/diagnostic-imaging&quot;&gt;Bracco Imaging&lt;/a&gt; in collaboration with some important Italian hospitals and research centers, was awarded as &quot;&lt;strong&gt;Best Scientific Collaboration Program of the Year&lt;/strong&gt;&quot; at &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;LIFE SCIENCE EXCELLENCE AWARD 2021&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The award is the most authoritative recognition that the &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;Popular Science magazine&lt;/span&gt; (published for almost 150 years in the United States), gives to projects of excellence, to innovative products and to scientists who have distinguished themselves in the last year in the scientific medical world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;AIforCOVID platform&lt;/span&gt; uses artificial intelligence algorithms capable of predicting the prognosis of &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;COVID-19 patients&lt;/span&gt; starting from x-rays and clinical data obtained at the time of hospital admission, in order to improve treatment and optimize the triage. At the end of the study, the results of the project were available to the entire international scientific community through the &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://aiforcovid.radiomica.it/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;AIforCOVID Imaging Archive data-sharing platform&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;                Rome, Italy                &lt;span class=&quot;date-display-single&quot;&gt;03/18/2022&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;ul class=&quot;links inline&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;translation_it-it first last&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/it/news/aiforcovid-best-scientific-collaboration-program-year&quot; title=&quot;AIforCOVID: “Best Scientific Collaboration Program of the Year”&quot; class=&quot;translation-link&quot; xml:lang=&quot;it-it&quot;&gt;Italiano&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 11:24:23 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">842 at https://www.bracco.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title> Bracco Imaging launches new subsidiary, Blue Earth Therapeutics, to advance  development of next generation therapeutic radiopharmaceutical technology</title>
 <link>https://www.bracco.com/en/news/bracco-imaging-launches-new-subsidiary-blue-earth-therapeutics-advance-development-next</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;form-item form-type-item&quot;&gt;
  &lt;label&gt;Language &lt;/label&gt;
 United Kingdom - English
&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Innovative &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;rhPSMA Theranostic technology&lt;/span&gt; has the potential to offer both diagnostic imaging and treatment for patients affected by prostate cancer. &lt;strong&gt;Blue Earth Therapeutics&lt;/strong&gt; has exclusive worldwide rights to therapeutic applications of radiohybrid Prostate-Specific Membrane Antigen (rhPSMA) radiopharmaceutical technology. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; “&lt;em&gt;We are increasingly committed to precision medicine,&lt;/em&gt;” says &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;Fulvio Renoldi Bracco&lt;/span&gt;, Vice-Chairman of the Board &amp;amp; CEO of Bracco Imaging SpA, the world leader in diagnostic imaging. “&lt;em&gt;Blue Earth Therapeutics will leverage the support of all &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;Bracco Imaging&lt;/span&gt;’s global capabilities and complementary portfolio to strengthen its high-value technology platform for innovative therapeutic radiopharmaceuticals, to care for cancer patients around the world. The creation of Blue Earth Therapeutics marks an exciting new direction for us in addressing important unmet needs in patient health.&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theranostic radiohybrid (rh) PSMA pharmaceuticals have potential utility in both diagnostic imaging and therapy of prostate cancer. They can be labelled with either a diagnostic or a therapeutic radioisotope. If approved, these innovative investigational compounds offer the possibility of personalized medicine for men with prostate cancer by directing therapies specifically to the PSMA disease target.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blue Earth Therapeutics has developed a highly optimized lead rhPSMA therapeutic compound, with a focus to increase the delivery of therapeutic radiation to kill tumors and minimize radiation exposure to healthy key organs such as kidney and bone marrow. Administering the lowest reasonably achievable radiation dose to normal tissues is a key principle of nuclear medicine, and particularly important when considering that therapeutic PSMA radioligands may be used earlier in prostate cancer disease progression in the future.&lt;/p&gt;  

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;We are very excited to launch Blue Earth Therapeutics during this renaissance of nuclear medicine, with the goal to fulfill the promise of targeted radiopharmaceutical therapy in treating patients with life-threatening disease,&lt;/em&gt;” says &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;David Gauden&lt;/span&gt;, D. Phil., Chief Executive Officer, Blue Earth Therapeutics. “&lt;em&gt;Blue Earth Therapeutics has demonstrable radiopharmaceutical therapy development expertise, and our initial efforts will address the growing patient treatment needs in prostate cancer, where we are currently advancing our flagship, next generation, 177Lu beta-emitting product candidate into clinical trials in the United States and EU. Initial investment in our company is provided by our founding shareholder, Bracco Imaging, and there are significant shared synergies with our sister company, &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;Blue Earth Diagnostics&lt;/span&gt;, which together provide Blue Earth Therapeutics a solid platform for future success. Near-term opportunities for further investment in the Blue Earth Therapeutics portfolio may include additional indications within prostate cancer for our initial product as well as development of alpha-emitting radiotherapeutics and development and licensing of new compounds in other cancer areas.&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blue Earth Therapeutics intends to build a pipeline of precision targeted therapeutic radiopharmaceuticals, initially focused on prostate cancer, and with plans to expand into additional disease areas in oncology. The Company is leveraging its radiopharmaceutical development experience, as demonstrated by the rapid success of its sister company Blue Earth Diagnostics, acquired by Bracco Imaging in 2019, to advance its nuclear medicine portfolio and apply its expertise to the world of next generation therapeutic radiopharmaceuticals.&lt;/p&gt;                 Milan, Italy                &lt;span class=&quot;date-display-single&quot;&gt;03/01/2022&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;ul class=&quot;links inline&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;translation_it-it first last&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/it/news/bracco-imaging-crea-blue-earth-therapeutics-sviluppare-la-tecnologia-radiofarmaceutica&quot; title=&quot;Bracco Imaging crea Blue Earth Therapeutics, per sviluppare la tecnologia radiofarmaceutica oncologica del futuro&quot; class=&quot;translation-link&quot; xml:lang=&quot;it-it&quot;&gt;Italiano&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 11:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">839 at https://www.bracco.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Read the new Bracco Group Sustainability Report</title>
 <link>https://www.bracco.com/en/news/read-new-bracco-group-sustainability-report</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;form-item form-type-item&quot;&gt;
  &lt;label&gt;Language &lt;/label&gt;
 United Kingdom - English
&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A transparent account of our sustainability actions and performance: this is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.braccoforasustainablefuture.com/en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Bracco Group Sustainability Report&lt;/a&gt;, the result of data and content collection that involved the main organisational areas of the Group at the global level. A communication tool that speaks about our attention to sustainability, in an economic, environmental and social sense and that tells about our way of acting today with an eye on the future. It defines the commitments we have assumed: first of all to safeguard the health and safety of patients and to ensure quality products and services, to reduce environmental impacts by limiting emissions and consumption, and to promote equality, diversity and welfare inside and outside the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;GIVING THE PLANET A NEW FUTURE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bracco believes that economic growth and sustainability, strategic business choices and protection of the environment must be combined. That’s why we innovate and improve products, services and processes to reduce emissions, responsibly manage natural resources and contribute to a circular economic model. We do this to guarantee the best possible future for new generations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;RESPONSIBLE SUPPLY CHAIN MANAGEMENT&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a relationship based on fairness and transparency, we agree with our suppliers on the principles of social and environmental responsibility that form the foundation of each phase of our business. Thus our commitment multiplies its positive impact on people, communities and the environment, generating a positive impact throughout the value chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;FOCUS ON PEOPLE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bracco values people&#039;s lives: our associates, healthcare operators, patients, and those living in the areas in which we operate. We guarantee an inclusive work environment that is attentive to well-being, where people can give their all to grow and develop increasingly better and safer high-quality products and services. We feel we are part of a community, and our commitment is to contribute to its growth. In this regard, in 2020 we fine-tuned an important diversity and inclusion policy, which is now being adopted by the entire Group throughout the world. Our commitment aims to always support a work environment free from any type of discrimination, whether direct or indirect, from any type of violence or harassment based on personal, political or cultural diversity, also engaging in an effective fight against gender stereotypes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;BUSINESS ETHICS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transparency and integrity are the values underlying our business. How we achieve our results is just as important as the results themselves. In our business vision, the company’s reputation and business successes are created through ethical business practices and relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul style=&quot;margin-bottom:25px;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Visit the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.braccoforasustainablefuture.com/en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bracco Group Sustainability Report&lt;/a&gt; website&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;cookieconsent-optout-marketing&quot;&gt;

    Please

    &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:Cookiebot.renew()&quot;&gt;accept marketing cookies&lt;/a&gt; 

    to view this video.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;460&quot; height=&quot;259&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/RUJwpkievVE&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;                Milan, Italy                &lt;span class=&quot;date-display-single&quot;&gt;01/24/2022&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;ul class=&quot;links inline&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;translation_it-it first last&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/it/news/leggi-il-nuovo-bilancio-di-sostenibilit-del-gruppo-bracco&quot; title=&quot;Leggi il nuovo Bilancio di Sostenibilità del Gruppo Bracco&quot; class=&quot;translation-link&quot; xml:lang=&quot;it-it&quot;&gt;Italiano&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 11:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">828 at https://www.bracco.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>en-Bracco top employer 2022</title>
 <link>https://www.bracco.com/en/en-bracco-top-employer-2022</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;form-item form-type-item&quot;&gt;
  &lt;label&gt;Language &lt;/label&gt;
 United Kingdom - English
&lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;field-label&quot;&gt;Sommario:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;/en/news/bracco-earns-top-employer-italia-2022&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;Bracco certified&lt;br&gt; for its optimal working conditions and its employee development policies&lt;/a&gt;          &lt;div class=&quot;field-label&quot;&gt;Immagine responsive 800x600:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.bracco.com/sites/bracco.com/files/bracco-top-employer-2022-800x600-1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;    &lt;ul class=&quot;links inline&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;translation_it-it first last&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/it/it-bracco-top-employer-2022&quot; title=&quot;it-Bracco top employer 2022&quot; class=&quot;translation-link&quot; xml:lang=&quot;it-it&quot;&gt;Italiano&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 13:52:42 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">821 at https://www.bracco.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Diana Bracco and Gianvito Vilé, winner of the Felder Award, appear at Trieste Next Festival to talk about scientific research and the brain drain</title>
 <link>https://www.bracco.com/en/news/diana-bracco-and-gianvito-vil-winner-felder-award-appear-trieste-next-festival-talk-about</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;form-item form-type-item&quot;&gt;
  &lt;label&gt;Language &lt;/label&gt;
 United Kingdom - English
&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;Diana Bracco&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;Gianvito Vilé&lt;/span&gt;, winner of the &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;Felder Award&lt;/span&gt;, were two of the participants at the ninth edition of “&lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;Trieste Next&lt;/span&gt;”, a national scientific research festival. Named after the great scientist Ernst Felder, the long-time head of the Bracco research division and discoverer of Iopamidol, a molecule that revolutionized diagnostic imaging, the Award, which includes a one-million-euro prize, was instituted by the Bracco Foundation, Bracco Imaging and Politecnico e Fondazione Politecnico di Milano with the purpose of attracting talented young Italian researchers who have moved abroad back to their home country. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the moderation of &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;Gabriele Beccaria&lt;/span&gt;, editor of the “Tuttoscienze” section of La Stampa newspaper, the discussions at Trieste Next reviewed the current state of research in Italy, paying particular attention to the situation of young scientists.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;&quot;&lt;em&gt;If there is one thing we need to learn from the terrible ordeal of the pandemic&lt;/em&gt;&quot;, observed Diana Bracco, Chair and CEO of the eponymous Bracco Group, &quot;&lt;em&gt;it is that we must never stop investing in research, for only science can protect us from current and future threats. Today the threat is &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;COVID-19&lt;/span&gt;; tomorrow, it might be the effects of &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;climate change&lt;/span&gt;. Meeting these challenges will require greater public and private investment, and a focus on &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;Life Sciences&lt;/span&gt;, which are of strategic importance. Italy has earned itself an estimable international reputation for the excellence of its scientific research, yet, measured as a percentage of GDP, national expenditure on research and innovation (R&amp;amp;I) places Italy in only 14&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; place in Europe, on a par with Spain and Greece. Italy spends less than half as much on R&amp;amp;I as Germany, Denmark and Austria. This is one of the reasons for my heartfelt hope that part of the resources from the &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;EU’s Recovery Fund&lt;/span&gt; will be channelled into &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;closing the R&amp;amp;I investment gap&lt;/span&gt;. Likewise, I hope that the government will make use of the resources of the &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;European Stability Mechanism&lt;/span&gt; to &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;revitalize the Italian national health service&lt;/span&gt; across the country.&lt;/em&gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;More generally,&lt;/em&gt;” continued Diana Bracco, “&lt;em&gt;only R&amp;amp;I is capable of creating permanent jobs that have no need of government subventions, and only R&amp;amp;I will lead to the production of quality goods that can compete successfully in international markets. The many excellent Italian companies in our sector are already well aware that the path to growth is through R&amp;amp;I, and the other companies need to acknowledge this fact and start moving in the right direction.&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking before an audience of students and researchers, Gianvito Vilé described his personal experience. After graduating from Politecnico di Milano, he moved to Switzerland, first to TU Delft and later to ETH in Zurich where he expanded his knowledge of certain aspects of Industrial Chemistry. &quot;&lt;em&gt;My desire, however, was always to return to Italy and put the skills I had honed with many years of international experience at the disposition of my own country.&lt;/em&gt;” he explained. The Felder Award helped him make his wish come true. His five-year research project is aimed at &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;designing new and environmentally sustainable new synthesis processes for contrast mediums&lt;/span&gt;, including both those already in commercial use and those still under development.&lt;/p&gt;                Trieste, Italy                &lt;span class=&quot;date-display-single&quot;&gt;01/18/2021&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;ul class=&quot;links inline&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;translation_it-it first last&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/it/news/trieste-next-diana-bracco-e-gianvito-vil-vincitore-del-premio-felder-parlano-di-ricerca-0&quot; title=&quot;A Trieste Next Diana Bracco e Gianvito Vilé, vincitore del Premio Felder, parlano di ricerca scientifica e fuga dei cervelli&quot; class=&quot;translation-link&quot; xml:lang=&quot;it-it&quot;&gt;Italiano&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 14:55:53 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">788 at https://www.bracco.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>The Bracco Foundation: ten years in the name of culture,  science and social engagement</title>
 <link>https://www.bracco.com/en/news/bracco-foundation-ten-years-name-culture-science-and-social-engagement</link>
 <description>&lt;div class=&quot;form-item form-type-item&quot;&gt;
  &lt;label&gt;Language &lt;/label&gt;
 United Kingdom - English
&lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I still recall the excitement I felt ten years ago when the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fondazionebracco.com/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot;&gt;Bracco Foundation&lt;/a&gt; was born. Supported by many friends, we gave life to a new institution that is rooted in the heritage of values acquired in the long &lt;a href=&quot;/en/group/history&quot;&gt;history&lt;/a&gt; of our Family and our Company: the ethic of responsibility, a sense of duty, the pursuit of quality and excellence, the pledge to constant innovation, focus on people and close links to communities. Key values, which together with my sister Gemma, Vice President of the Foundation, we wish to pass on to the next generation. Values to which we have always aspired, in the belief that they also represent the best guarantee for being able to overcome difficult times, such as for example what we are now experiencing in the &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;Covid pandemic&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;/en/group&quot;&gt;Bracco Group&lt;/a&gt;, for that matter, truly has philanthropy in its DNA. My father Fulvio, an enlightened and visionary player in post-war industry, strongly believed in “taking care” and in the “moral” relationship between companies, the territory and the environment. An Istrian exile, he also felt a profound need for “restitution”, to give back, therefore, a part of what his company had created to the community. Already in the post-war period, &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;Fulvio Bracco&lt;/span&gt; for example instituted study scholarships dedicated to his mother “Nina Salata’s” name, which are somewhat the “ancestors” of our youth projects.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reaching the finishing line of &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;10 years&lt;/span&gt;, we can state with pride that the &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;Bracco Foundation&lt;/span&gt; has reached the objectives that we had set ourselves. We created many projects that have produced positive and concrete results, certified moreover by the social impact evaluation instruments that we have adopted.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The three macro-areas in which we operate, combining knowledge, disciplines and perspectives, are &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;science, culture and social projects&lt;/span&gt;, with particular attention always to the world of women and to the young, to whom we have dedicated the project “&lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;I will become&lt;/span&gt;” (progetto Diventerò), a specific long-term training and job placement project that up to today has allocated over one thousand awards for degrees, study scholarships and research doctorates. Among these is the award we have dedicated to the memory of &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;Prof. Ernst Felder&lt;/span&gt;, a brilliant scientist who for many years headed the Bracco Research Department and whose discoveries revolutionised diagnostic imaging. It is an award in partnership with the Milan Polytechnic Foundation worth one million euros with the objective of bringing a young, talented researcher back to our Country.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Bracco Foundation believes that science is profoundly linked to &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;research, prevention and sustainable development&lt;/span&gt;, but also to &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;gender equality&lt;/span&gt;. We are running a comprehensive project in this area, “&lt;a href=&quot;/en/news/100-women-science&quot;&gt;100 women against stereotypes&lt;/a&gt;”, which through a database, a book series and a photographic exhibition wishes to focus the spotlight on science for women and the skills of women in sectors that are strategic for the development of the Country.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gazing back on our cultural activities in these years, I recall some of them with particular pleasure; the restoration of the Chigi Gallery in the Quirinale Palace on the occasion of the 150&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; anniversary of the Unity of Italy, the exhibitions at the National Gallery of Washington, aimed at sustaining and enhancing Italian art abroad, the now ten-year long and multidisciplinary support given to talented young people at the Teatro alla Scala Academy and the close relationship with the Poldi Pezzoli Museum in Milan, all high quality projects, not simple disbursements of money, developed through prestigious partnerships that have created added cultural and scientific value.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/sites/bracco.com/files/sala-gialla-quirinale-restaurata-fondazione-bracco.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;The restoration of the Alessandro VII Chigi Gallery, Quirinale Palace&quot; width=&quot;475&quot; height=&quot;322&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 13px!important;&quot;&gt;The restoration of the Alessandro VII Chigi Gallery, Quirinale Palace&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/sites/bracco.com/files/canaletto-national-gallery.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;Canaletto, National Gallery of Washington&quot; width=&quot;475&quot; height=&quot;324&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 13px!important;&quot;&gt;Canaletto, National Gallery of Washington&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Over these years, many of our cultural initiatives have been dedicated to the combination of art and science. Imaging techniques, in fact, allow us to reveal many “secrets” in works of art (paintings, musical instruments, etc.), and for us, leaders in the world of image diagnosis, it was natural to make our skills in this field available to curators and restorers. For instance, I recall the exhibition “&lt;a href=&quot;/en/news/all-secrets-caravaggio-revealed-x-radiography&quot;&gt;Inside Caravaggio&lt;/a&gt;” at the Royal Palace in Milan, in which the public was guided in the discovery of this great artist through an itinerary of “X-ray” videos placed alongside the paintings, and the project “Leonardesque artists beyond the visible”, which  dealt with the scientific study of works by Leonardo’s pupils in the scope of activities supporting the exhibition “Leonardo and the Litta Madonna” at the Poldi Pezzoli Museum in Milan, during the year of celebrations of the 500 year anniversary of the death of this Italian genius par excellence.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Although it also has an international vocation, over the last ten years the Foundation has remained closely linked to the &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;city of Milan&lt;/span&gt;, paying particular attention to social aspects and the topic of enhancing our suburbs, which has become an absolute priority. We are in fact aware that if steps are not taken in relation to the urban fabric, problems degenerate in a dramatic way, as can be witnessed in the recent history concerning many European metropolitan areas. There is a cost to not acting in society. For this reason we are increasingly involved in this field.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A very important contribution has been achieved for example in the Municipality of Baranzate. At the beginning of 2016, in partnership with La Rotonda, the association created by Don Paolo Steffano, in one of the most multiethnic Milanese suburbs, the project “&lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;Beyond the Margins&lt;/span&gt;” was born, a highly complex enterprise based on the needs and on the isolation of the territory. The project is a model for services interpreted through three principal axes of activities: social inclusion through the workplace (with the sewing workshop “Fiori all’Occhiello”), health care for marginalised people and tackling of educational poverty. But we have not stopped there. We have invested in the construction of a place of inclusion and care, social participation and entrepreneurship in Baranzate, the “&lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;InOltre&lt;/span&gt;” space, an ex-industrial hangar which will become an important resource for the creation of a centre in the suburbs. A place of social regeneration based on &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;hospitality, solidarity and multi-culturism&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So far I have lingered on some of the most important projects that we have implemented in the Bracco Foundation’s first ten years of activity. To celebrations and anniversaries, after all, we entrust the task of remembrance. The role of &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;memory&lt;/span&gt;, nevertheless, is not just that of recalling the successes of the past but also one of providing us with a compass to map out the correct path for the &lt;span class=&quot;keybold&quot;&gt;future&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is because of this that we have conceived the book &quot;10 voices for 10 years. Words that impact&quot; as a sort of small “encyclopaedia” composed of reflections by ten distinguished friends on an equal number of words that represent the Bracco Foundation best: culture, science, art, music, talent, woman, solidarity, sustainability, knowledge and thought. Cardinal concepts that, since 2010, have guided our choices and will continue to inspire the work done by the Foundation also in the future.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diana Bracco&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterword of the book: &quot;10 voices for 10 years. Words that impact&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;                Milan, Italy                &lt;span class=&quot;date-display-single&quot;&gt;01/18/2021&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;ul class=&quot;links inline&quot;&gt;&lt;li class=&quot;translation_it-it first last&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/it/news/fondazione-bracco-dieci-anni-nel-segno-di-cultura-scienza-e-impegno-sociale&quot; title=&quot;Fondazione Bracco: dieci anni nel segno di cultura, scienza e impegno sociale&quot; class=&quot;translation-link&quot; xml:lang=&quot;it-it&quot;&gt;Italiano&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
 <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 14:19:52 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">786 at https://www.bracco.com</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
